<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Chapter 6: The Ariester</Title>
     <Data><![CDATA[<p>Merscythe turned his attention to Herv, who had started coughing and sputtering again. The little man pushed himself up. “We’re not safe here,” he said. “Follow me.” He scrambled up the ladder in the center of the room, and Merscythe followed. It deposited them in a round wooden room very much like Loog’s, but clearly belonging to a younger man. There was a small bed off to the side, and a huge couch and television in the center of the room. Merscythe wondered what kind of shows elves and gnomes watched. There was a tidy kitchen off to one side, which smelled delicious. A narrow spiral staircase led up and out of sight.</p><p>Herv pulled the ladder up into the room and sealed the hatch. He turned to Merscythe and asked, “Soup?”</p><p>It took Merscythe a second to understand what he meant. “Soup?” he replied, puzzled.</p><p>Herv gestured to a teapot sitting on the stove. “I made us some soup,” he explained.</p><p>Merscythe was even more confused. “Shouldn't we be looking for Loog?”</p><p>Herv walked over to the stove and flipped a switch. Almost immediately, the kettle started steaming and humming. He flipped the switch again and poured two piping-hot bowls of soup. “This kind of thing happens,” he explained to Merscythe </break>grimly. “We can’t just panic or worse, stop drinking soup. Sip, and let’s plan.”</p><p>Merscythe sipped the soup gently. There were mushrooms and earthy root vegetables in it. He hadn't realized how hungry he had been and it tasted delicious. It scalded his tongue, but also washed away the acrid taste of smoke in his mouth. “What are we going to do?” he asked.</p><p>Herv paused and sipped his soup as well before responding. “If Verin’s forces have Loog, we’re not going to be able to rescue him on our own. We’re going to need a ship.”</p><p>“Wait,” said Merscythe, “Verin? I thought it was Ari.”</p><p>Herv snorted. “How many times do I have to tell, you, kid, Ari’s in prison. Even if she isn’t, this wasn’t her style. Ari’s dangerous, but her handiwork shows some finesse. Explosions and kidnappings are more Verin’s thing.”</p><p>Merscythe sat down on one of the chairs. “What’s the deal with Verin anyway?”</p><p>Herv’s face darkened. “You might be wondering why we live up here instead of in the city below. Commander Verin’s got a massive network of spies and informants, and we’re not exactly his biggest fans. A couple of years ago, when he first started locking dissenters up, we tried speaking out. So did Ari, actually—although no one knows why. But too many of </break>our friends were imprisoned. We had to move up here to stay safe. There’s a whole secret neighborhood in the crust of the earth now, below your world and above ours. Ari had her lab up here too, but Verin found her and caught her. It’s only a matter of time before we’re next.” That made sense to Merscythe, but something was still off.</p><p>“But then why didn’t he kidnap you?”</p><p>“You know, I’m wondering that too,” replied Herv, almost indignantly. “I thought I’d be important enough for them to capture.</p><p>“Okay, so it was Verin. How are we going to rescue Loog, though? I thought no one ever escaped from Verin’s prison,” Merscythe said. “Except Ari,” he added, and Herv scowled at him.</p><p>“I have an idea,” the gnome replied. “It’s not a great idea, but it’s a start. We need a ship, and it just so happens that Ari left one lying around.”</p><p>“What do you mean, a ship?” asked Merscythe. “Like a boat?”</p><p>Herv waved a dismissive hand. “No, kid, not a boat. Like a spaceship, or a plane. When Ari was captured, her Ariester was left somewhere in the crust.”</p><p>“Okay,” replied Merscythe, “but what about it?”</p></break><p>“Well, obviously, we’re going to need to commandeer it.”</p><p>“Commandeer?”</p><p>“As in, we need to requisition her ship.”</p><p>“What are you talking about?” Merscythe asked.</p><p>Herv sighed. “Borrow,” he explained. “We need to borrow her ship.”</p><p>It dawned on Merscythe what Herv was suggesting. “We can’t just steal her ship!” he exclaimed.</p><p>Herv sighed. “Ari’s in prison, remember? She’s not going to miss it for a few days.” Merscythe had to admit that they didn’t exactly have a better plan to save Loog.</p><p>“So where is this ship?”</p><p>Wordlessly, Herv opened the hatch in the center of the room and climbed down to the observatory. Merscythe followed him into the damaged elevator. Herv indicated floor 13, and the elevator skyrocketed upward.</p><p>The gaping hole in the doors made the elevator ride even more surreal. Merscythe was buffeted by the howling wind, certain that he was going to be blown out. The elevator shaft occasionally flashed white as they whizzed past a well-lit floor. Merscythe braced himself as they approached floor 13, but even then he was tossed into the air as they screeched to a </break>halt.</p><p>The doors slid open to reveal a massive, empty hangar. The walls were gleaming white, with a grey garage door on the far side. “There it stands,” grinned Herv.</p><p>Merscythe stared, but the hangar was clearly empty. Herv motioned to him to keep walking forward, so he took a few steps forward. He looked back at Herv, who impatiently motioned to him again. Merscythe had walked about twenty steps when he gasped.</p><p>A huge white ship, longer than a jumbo jet, seemed to have appeared out of nowhere. Merscythe walked around it in awe. It was sleek and modern, with a small cockpit on top and swept-back wings built into the body. He couldn’t see an engine, but there was a massive exhaust at the back. The front tapered to a point. A set of lights was gently pulsing on top of the ship, but the cockpit seemed deserted.</p><p>“I present the Ariester,” chuckled Herv. “It’s Ari’s invention and I have to admit, it’s really clever. It’s coated with a unique metal that bends light in three dimensions, so that color from the surroundings reflects around it to make it invisible. You can only see it when you’re close enough to the inner periphery of the light rays.”</p><p>Merscythe was still awestruck. “How did you know it was </break> here?”</p><p>“Ari and Loog have had a couple of close shaves. The last time, he put a tracking device on the bottom and followed it here. It hasn’t moved since Ari got captured.”</p><p>“So then why haven’t you stolen—er, commandeered it before?” Merscythe asked.</p><p>Herv frowned. “We’ve had a couple of problems entering in the past. That’s where you come in.” He and Merscythe walked underneath the ship toward the left side. Merscythe had to duck slightly. On the other side, they climbed a set of metal steps that led up to a thick white door with a small porthole for peeking in. The inside of the ship was dark, but the door was sealed tight. To its right, there were five shimmering concentric dials, each numbered zero to nine. “The entrance is locked with a secret code,” Herv explained. “You’re going to have to crack it.”</p> ]]>
    </Data>
</Chapter>