<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Chapter 3: Through the Caverns</Title>
     <Data><![CDATA[<p>Merscythe frantically punched “Ari” into the screen. To his relief, the siren stopped wailing and the lights turned back on. He decided to try the other doors first; he had to get out of this place before the diminutive trio returned.</p> <p>But his curiosity got the better of him in this strange lab. Merscythe walked around the perimeter of the room. He took a glass vial off of the lowest shelf and uncapped it. Immediately, the blue liquid inside turned silver and started to bubble and foam, making a high-pitched humming sound. He quickly capped the vial and put it back on the shelf. The humming stopped, and the liquid turned blue again.</p><p>He tried turning on one of the faucets on the wall, but nothing happened. Surprised, he tried turning on the next one and had to jump out of the way as a black liquid sputtered out and onto the ground. The liquid evaporated the second it hit the floor, making a gentle sizzling sound.  He turned this tap off and tried a third one. A jet of white-hot flames hissed out, and he quickly closed it, deciding that maybe this wasn’t such a good idea. Instead, he tried pushing open one of the room's three smaller doors.</p><p>It was sealed as tightly as the first one. He tried sliding it open and pushed it as hard as he could, with no luck. Frustrated, he kicked it, and to his surprise, it swung open. He peeked inside, hoping this was a way out. His heart sank as he realized it wasn’t. The room was dark and tiny, like a small </break> closet. In the gloom, he could make out shelves of hundreds of dusty books. He looked at the spines of a couple—“The Discerning Fugitive’s Guide to Invisibility” and “Fifty Ways to Genetically Modify Your Friends”—before walking back to the lab.</p><p>Merscythe stepped around the three cages and tried pushing the next door. It was sealed as well. Pressing his ear to the door, he heard a rhythmic breathing within, like the snoring of a large dog. He decided against kicking this one. The last door he tried was unlocked! But it swung open to reveal just another closet, even narrower than the library. The room had the acrid smell of burning metal. He looked around and saw dozens of carefully arranged rows of small steel squares that seemed to change color as he watched. Confused, he stepped back into the lab.</p><p>He spent the next few minutes looking for a hidden exit in the room, but with no luck. Exasperated, Merscythe returned to the first door and tried pushing it again. He even kicked it, but it didn’t work. He sat down on the floor and realized he was exhausted. He didn’t know what time it was, or where he was, or how long he’d been there. His family would be terrified—that is, if they’d even noticed he was missing through the chaos of the reunion. He missed his mother, his Aunt Arabella, Gobbler’s Knob, even Croy—well, Croy not so much. He was </break>trapped in a strange laboratory with murderous midgets running around, and somehow, unbelievably, he’d made green flames appear with his bare hands. Overwhelmed and drained, with these frightening, wondrous thoughts floating through his mind, Merscythe feebly pushed against the door again. Then he remembered the strange calculator that was in his pocket. He pulled it out and examined it. On closer inspection, it couldn’t be a calculator at all. Its edges were clearly worn out, but the screen was bright and colorful, with a full keyboard below it. Inscribed at the bottom were the words “Codue 0413”, and at the top was an inactive orange light. Suddenly, the orange light started flashing. He stood up. A program appeared on the screen.</p>]]>
	</Data>
</Chapter>