<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Chapter 4: Little Men and Long Beards</Title>
     <Data><![CDATA[<p>To Merscythe’s relief, the door finally swung open and he stepped through. The room he was in was cold and dark, nothing like the vast, gleaming lab he had just left. As his eyes adjusted to the gloom, he saw that he was in some kind of cave with damp stone walls and dangling cobwebs. The smooth tile floor had given way to brown earth, and the air was crisp and cool. One side of the cave had a large, perfectly circular hole in the wall, with light flickering on the other side. Merscythe walked to the hole and cautiously poked his head through it. There was another deserted room there, with a staircase leading down. The light was coming from two dim torches set into the walls. Merscythe wriggled his way through the hole and descended the steps. At the bottom was a long passage that curved out of sight. He walked down it. The stone walls were lined with shelves of mysterious jars: some with liquids, and others with stuff that Merscythe didn’t want to know about. At the end of the passageway, he found a bright, jewel-encrusted door. Pushing it open, he gasped.</p><p>It was another cavern, but this one was completely covered in shimmering brown gems that Merscythe had never seen before. The floor, the walls, everything was glittering as light reflected off the strange stones. Their beauty was mesmerizing. After the gloom of the other caves, Merscythe could barely look at the gleaming gems, but he also couldn’t take his eyes off them. Stepping forward, he heard some of </break>them shift under his feet. There was an open door at the other side of the room, and he walked over to it. As he was leaving, he pocketed one of the smaller stones. Ari wouldn’t miss one, right?</p><p></p>On the left side of the next room was a pair of metal doors. Merscythe tried pushing the doors open, before realizing there was a button on the left. He hoped no one had seen that. He pushed the button, and the doors opened soundlessly. As he stepped through, the doors slid shut behind him.</p><p>He was in yet another stone hallway, which seemed to curve infinitely in both directions. He was wondering which way he should go, when he heard a massive roar come from the right corridor. <i>Well, that solves that problem,</i> he thought, as he began running down the left corridor. He looked behind him, expecting to see some terrifying beast.</p><p>It was, in fact, a tiny man with a huge beard sprinting toward him. Merscythe stopped running, and waited for him to catch up. "Run, you idiot!" the man shouted. He looked terrified. Merscythe was about to ask why, when he looked behind the man and saw a gargantuan brown mass bounding toward them. It was, without a doubt, the largest guinea pig that Merscythe had ever seen. It was almost as tall as the short man. However, Merscythe didn't see the threat. After all, he was a good two feet taller than it. The creature roared, </break>spewing a burst of orange flames directly at the man and Merscythe. Somehow, the creature seemed much more menacing with fire billowing from its nostrils. Merscythe ran faster.</p><p>"What is it?" yelled Merscythe to the man.</p><p>"Genetically modified capybara! Breathes fire!" the man explained, wheezing as he ran.</p><p>"Capy-what? And how can it even do that?"</p><p>"I would guess a piezoelectric crystal begins the catalytic combustion of stored methane and oxygen ejected through the respiratory tract, perhaps berlinite—"</p><p>"And what is that in English?" Merscythe interrupted, panting.</p><p>"Sparks make fire! The creature must be completely heatproof!" Suddenly, the man grabbed him. "Stop!" he said.</p><p>"What?" Merscythe yelled. "Are you crazy?"</p><p>"Stop running! We'll tire sooner than it will. It'll catch us anyway! Just trust me!"</p><p>"And why should I trust you?"</p><p>"Because, Merscythe, it's the only way you'll live."</p><p>Merscythe gasped. How did the man know his name? With this sudden shock, he took a leap of faith. He stopped and </break> stared directly at his pursuer, the capy-whatever. The animal bellowed, and the flames engulfed Merscythe. But they didn't burn him. He stared, and saw green flames flickering around his arm. He felt a sharp pain in his head, and sent a massive wave of green fire down the corridor. The creature squealed at the cold and was thrown backwards. Merscythe fell to his knees, and blacked out.</p><p>             * * *              </p><p>He awoke to find the little man with the long beard leaning over him. Merscythe was lying on a bed that surprisingly fit him. The man wore sunglasses. Why anyone would need sunglasses when they were underground was a mystery to Merscythe, but he thought it would be rude to ask.</p><p>“Aha!” said the man. “So, you're awake.”</p><p><i>Why does everyone say 'Aha!' here?</i> wondered Merscythe. Aloud, he asked, “Where am I?”</p><p>“In my house.”</p><p>Merscythe stood up, and his head hit the ceiling.</p><p>“Watch the roof,” the man said.</p><p>“Thanks,” grumbled Merscythe. The stone caverns were gone, replaced by a small wooden hut. There were pots and pans piled in a sink on one side, a rickety-looking beach chair in the </break>corner, and a huge, comfortable bed in the middle of the hut’s only room.</p><p>Merscythe sat back down on the bed and asked, “Who are you?”</p><p>“Me? I am Loog,” said the short guy with the long beard.</p><p>“Loog? That's a really weird name.”</p><p>“You’re one to talk, <i>Merscythe</i>,” replied Loog.</p><p>Merscythe remembered how they had escaped earlier. “How do you know my name?” Then, a more startling realization struck him. “And how did you know about the green fire?”</p><p>“Lucky guess?” said Loog quickly. Too quickly.</p><p>“You're lying. What happened? Tell me now!”</p><p>“Okay. You are…talented. You are able to perform extraordinary feats. That’s why you knew to come underground, and that’s how I knew you were here. But it’s not safe in the abandoned lab, so I brought you here. It wasn’t as abandoned as I had believed.” The man shuddered, remembering the fire-breathing rodent.</p><p>“Abandoned? What about Ari and her henchmen?” asked Merscythe.</p><p>“What? Ari?!”</p></break><p>Merscythe narrated his story. Loog’s eyes widened when he said that Ari had tried to take his blood. When he was finished, the bearded man looked pale.</p><p>“If what you say is true, then no one is safe. Ari…no. This isn't true. It can't be. Ari is in prison. Commander Verin has taken her.”</p><p>“Commander Verin?”</p><p>“Verin is an evil man. He is the commander of the Underground Force of Safety (a.k.a. UFOS or the cops). Everything he does involves a squad armed with very, very big guns. The only thing he can do is deal with criminals. He sticks them on a heatproof rock surrounded by lava. No one has escaped, and no one ever will. He captures even the law-abiding citizens who don’t like him, including me. Ari is trapped, kid.”</p><p>“No, she's not. I saw her with my own eyes. She tried to take my blood. I don't know why, but I’m telling you, it's true.”</p><p>“Well, if what you say is true, we'll know very soon.”</p><p>“How?”</p><p>“Because Ari will be back. And extremely angry.” Loog beckoned Merscythe to follow him out of the hut.</p><p>The front door of the hut led to a long, narrow corridor. They </break> stopped in front of glass elevator. “Where are we going?” Merscythe asked Loog suspiciously, as he ushered Merscythe into the elevator.</p><p>“You'll see,” said Loog mysteriously. “Take us to floor minus 10.”</p><p>Merscythe looked at the buttons, then looked back at him, surprised. “The buttons only go from 1 to 50.”</p><p>Loog grinned. “Your Codue can take us there.”</p><p>Merscythe cast a sidelong look at the man. How did he know so much? He removed the Codue from his pocket and noticed that the now-familiar orange light was flashing again.</p>]]>
</Data>
</Chapter>