<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Chapter 8: Through the Lava Pit</Title>
     <Data><![CDATA[ <p>“Almost there.” Ari said. Of course, this was rather unnecessary. The heat was already scorchingly unbearable, and had been growing steadily for minutes now. Drops of perspiration fell from Herv's forehead, but Merscythe wondered if that was from anxiety of the situation they were headed into. Then it struck him. What would happen if they were captured? Would he be stuck in a rock forever unable to get out? Would he see his family again? He missed them more than ever.</p><p>These thoughts were cut short by a siren that blared throughout the ship. “Left engine is overheating,” called Ari from ahead. She looked back from the cockpit and yelled over the wailing siren. “Okay, human! Conjure your fire!”</p><p>“What?” Merscythe was puzzled. “I told you! I can't just conjure it on command!”</p><p>After a moment, Herv yelled, “Heat!” as if he was realizing something.</p><p>“What?” shouted Merscythe. “It's hot enough already!”</p><p>“No, your fire! Ari, open the hatch!” Herv was shouting at the top of his lungs.</p><p>Merscythe gaped. “But we'll—”</p><p>"Do it!" he screamed.</p></break><p>Ari hesitated for a moment, then Herv’s plan seemed to dawn on her. She pushed a button and a wave of heat engulfed the ship as a door opened behind them. Merscythe fell, and felt the pain in his head return. He shut his eyes, and felt a wave of cold air rush over him. Green flames flew through the hatch and around the ship. The siren stopped, and Ari closed the rear hatch as Merscythe collapsed to the floor. He was exhausted, but not as much as he was the last time he conjured fire. Maybe he was getting used to it, or maybe it was just the adrenaline of the situation.</p><p>“Almost through the pit—a few more seconds to go,” said Ari, looking unfazed as she guided the ship through swerving paths, glancing at the Codue occasionally. “Okay, we're through, but the fire lit us like a beacon. The metal coating is damaged and the ship is visible. I have a UFOS ship on our trail. We have twelve minutes to pick up Loog and get away before they catch up with us. There are two parts to the lava prison - the east and the west. Anyone want to take a wild guess which part he is in? Twelve minutes isn’t enough time to search both.”</p><p>Merscythe and Herv were quiet.</p><p>“Thanks,” said Ari. “I’ll image the area with my terahertz scanner, and find a spot that's shaped like him.”</p><p>“That'll never work, but it's worth a try, I suppose,” said Herv. </break>They crowded around the screen and saw a person who appeared to have long beard.</p><p>“That has to be him,” said Merscythe. “He's on the eastern side.”</p><p>The ship swooped down over the eastern part of the prison and Ari, Merscythe and Herv did a quick reconnaissance of the area. Built of monolithic lava rock, it was huge and rocky with a desolate look. "There he is," exclaimed Merscythe pointing out Loog, who was lying on a rock. The ship hovered above him and a giant vacuum extricator pulled him in.</p><p>Loog looked terrible. His beard was dirty and matted, and his skin was pale white. Reeli brought him two bottles of water. Merscythe watched him pour the entirety of the first one into his mouth. His hands were shaking, but he seemed relieved to have been rescued. He lay down without saying a word as he tried to recover his strength.</p><p>The UFOS were catching up with them. Ari spun the ship around. Her eyes were flashing. She seemed to be enjoying the chase as she changed speeds and swung the ship around. “The UFOS can’t follow us over the lava pit.”</p><p>“Merscythe, we'll need you to conjure fire again as we go over the pit,” Herv said.</p><p>“I…I don't think I can,” Merscythe quivered. The first wave of</break> fire had nearly taken all of his energy. He had managed to stay awake, but only just.</p><p>“Don't think about the pain in your head. Think about the flames. Be them. Control them. Use their energy, don't make them use yours.”</p><p>“I'll t-try.” Merscythe's voice was shaky. He stood up, balancing precariously.</p><p>“We are reaching lava in three...two...one...” A wave of heat hit them, and and Merscythe tried to do what Herv said. He focused. He pushed. He tried with all his might, but no flames shot out of his hands. Ari had dropped the hatch once more. Merscythe strained, but a loud siren began screeching. He lost his concentration and fell back.</p><p>“It's no good! I can't do it! I'm sorry,” Merscythe shouted.</p><p>“Don't be. Drink this.” It was Loog. He handed Merscythe a bottle of ice-cold water. Merscythe felt better, but he still had little energy, and he sat back.</p><p>“Concentrate on being the fire. Use it to your advantage. You can do it,” said Herv.</p><p>Merscythe thought, and as soon as Herv said that, he saw the flames dance on his arm. He heard words in his head, and he listened. He whispered, “Asa kalaad,” as the flames bowed to his command. They spread around this ship, forming a sort of </break>force-field of flames. The siren stopped. He was no longer a person—he felt as if he was a part of the world. He could move the fire and arrange it as easily as he would move a book from a table. He opened his eyes, and he could no longer control the flames, but they still burned around the ship, filling the windows with green light.</p><p>“How did you make the flames follow the ship?” asked Ari in amazement.</p><p>“They're not following the ship, Ari,” said Loog. “They're following him.”</p><p>They flew over the lava pit, steadily rising. Then they went through the exit, and flew away. The green fire evaporated into nothing, and the ship flickered into invisibility.</p><p>             * * *           </p><p>Herv and Loog sat at a table with Merscythe. They were back in Herv's house, sipping soup around the small table.</p><p>“I need to go back,” said Merscythe. “Back home.” He could only imagine what would be going on aboveground. His parents must have been worried sick.</p><p>“Of course, but going to the surface isn't as easy as coming down.” said Loog. "I will do my best to provide you safe transport."</p></break><p>Merscythe had the fleeting image of Loog dragging him to the tube that he fell through in Ari's lab and kicking him up it, while everyone yelled, “Bye!” from below. The thought left his mind as quickly as it came.</p><p>“The easiest way is by elevator.” Herv said. “There happens to be one not very far from here.” Herv beckoned Merscythe to the long staircase, and they walked down it. Herv led him through a set of sloping passageways. “Here we are!” Merscythe stopped and stared at the largest glass elevator he had ever seen. It was incredibly grand, and filled with the most intricate carvings and Argenglass sculptures he had ever seen.</p><p>“Floor Aboveground, please!” said Merscythe, walking in and staring in amazement.</p><p>“It doesn't work exactly like that,” chuckled Herv, who pressed a series of buttons on the side panel. “Goodbye, Merscythe.”</p><p>“Wait, but—” Merscythe's protests were cut short as Herv stepped out.</p><p>“Don't worry, I'll see you soon,” said Herv, winking. And after that unceremonious farewell, the doors shut, and the floor began to move upward. The ground moved up so quickly that Merscythe was pushed flat against the floor. It moved faster and faster, until the city below was a blur. After about an hour, </break>he saw light above. He reached the top and was thrown out by the elevator, up a hole, and on the Earth, with the grass doing little to cushion his fall. He landed directly on his head, and combined with the exhaustion he already felt, a lead feeling took over him, and he fell asleep.</p><p>Merscythe awoke with his mother by him. He was in his bed, in his house, in his regular life. “Oh Merscythe, you're awake! Thank goodness! You were gone for hours before Great-Uncle Gool found you asleep by the tree. We tried to wake you up, but—”</p><p>“Wait, thirty minutes?” asked Merscythe. He was sure he had been gone for four days, at least.</p><p>“Yes, we were worried sick. Well, I'll let you get some rest,” she left the room.</p><p>Merscythe was confused, but he had a dull pounding in his head and he was still tired, so he fell asleep again, with the Codue's orange light gently pulsing in his outstretched arm.</p>]]>
</Data>
</Chapter>