<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Chapter 5: Apella, Loftar, and Miton</Title>
     <Data><![CDATA[<p>The elevator plummeted down so fast that Merscythe had to grab the handrail to avoid flying up and hitting the ceiling. Then, almost as suddenly, it slammed to a halt. Merscythe was thrown to the floor as the doors slid open again. Pushing himself up, he stepped out and stopped dead with shock.</p>
<p>“Here we are!” said Loog happily.</p>
<p>The elevator had deposited them in a huge, circular room made almost entirely of glass. The floor, the walls, even the furniture was completely clear. But what astounded Merscythe was what he saw below. It was night outside, but there were no stars or clouds in the sky. The circular room was suspended at least a mile above some sort of vast city. Skyscrapers with lights twinkling in their windows sprawled as far as he could see. Despite the dark, the city seemed vibrant and alive. Merscythe had thought he was underground, so how was there a whole city down there?</p>
<p>Loog walked out of the elevator casually, but Merscythe was rooted to the spot. The man turned and beckoned him forward.</p>
<p>“Is it strong enough to hold us both?” Merscythe asked.</p>
<p>“Yeah,” replied Loog. “It’s Argenglass. Glass mixed with an argentite alloy. As strong as metal and as clear as glass.”</p>
<p>Merscythe gingerly took a step forward. The Argenglass floor seemed to hold his weight, but he was too terrified to look </break>down. The tip of the tallest building was still at least half a mile below him. Looking around the room, he saw that it seemed to be some kind of observatory. The ceiling appeared to be wooden, and had a small hatch built into it. There were small chairs around the perimeter of the room, a sofa in one corner, and at the far end, a huge black telescope.</p>
<p>“Okay, what is this world?” Merscythe asked Loog, awestruck. The man chuckled and began to explain.</p>
<p>The world below was a huge country. Each day, nuclear fusion powered an artificial sun overhead. Loog told Merscythe that the country comprised three lands—Apella, Loftar, and Miton. Each land had a residential section and a downtown section. The malls were mainly patronized by adolescent gnomes and elves buying clothes or checking out the newest electronics. The males were gnomes and females were elves. Nearly all the residents were peace-loving people, with a couple of exceptions. And the society as a whole was progressive and scientific, decades ahead of humans in what they had managed to develop. Loog beckoned Merscythe toward the telescope.</p> 
<p>Merscythe peeked through it and gaped, astounded. Even in the dark, the clarity was remarkable. He could make out individual people walking along the city streets, stopping at market booths or rushing into buildings. They all seemed to be Loog’s size, but Merscythe couldn’t really tell. Everyone </break>looked tiny compared to the massive skyscrapers that crowded the skyline.  He pointed the telescope at a couple of different buildings. In one, he saw a meeting taking place, with elves and gnomes in business suits yelling at each other. Another had dozens of floors of fancy restaurants, with dim candlelight flickering in the windows. A third one looked like a science lab, with dozens of men and women in white coats frantically extinguishing a fire. The whole place felt more vibrant and alive than anywhere Merscythe had ever been—and loads more exciting than quiet little Gobbler’s Knob.</p>
<p>He tore his eyes from the sights below to see Loog press a button next to the elevator doors. A doorbell sounded and a hanging microphone descended from the ceiling. Loog grabbed the mike and shouted “Loog!”</p>
<p>“Loog?” a muffled voice responded from the hatch in the ceiling. “What is it now? If you want that potion to turn people into rats, I still need four human fingernails and moldy cheese!”</p>
<p>“Hold off on the potion for now, Herv. I got someone you might want to meet.”</p>
<p>“All right. But if it’s a dragon, once was more than enough.”</p>
<p>Herv opened the hatch and a ladder dropped down. He started climbing the ladder, and Merscythe got his first glimpse of the man. Herv was also three feet tall and looked </break> much younger than Loog, as he was clean-shaven with wavy blond hair. He had climbed halfway down when he saw Merscythe standing there. His brown eyes widened.</p>
<p>"Hu…hu…hu...EEK!"</p>
<p>Herv would have scampered back up and joined the circus in hiding, but the older gnome grabbed his foot and yanked Herv to the ground.</p>
<p>“You were born to teach wizards magic. Or did you forget?” growled Loog.</p>
<p>Herv said, “I can only teach wizards. Not some random kid who fell down here.”</p>
<p>“Why else do you think I came, you dolt! This kid is magical! He’s the last wizard left. What’s more, Ari is after his blood. She’s escaped!”</p>
<p>There was a stunned silence for a second, which was broken by Herv chuckling loudly. “Yeah, right. Ari’s escaped. Listen to me! Ari’s dead. She’s been locked up for 2 years.”</p>
<p>“Don’t ask me how. But she’s back. What will it take for you to believe me?”</p>
<p>“Proof,” replied Herv.</p>
<p>“Whatever. The point is, I need you to train him. He’s the only one powerful enough to stop Verin.”</p> </break>
<p>“How powerful?”</p>
<p>“Two words. Asa kalaad.”</p>
<p>“No way. Impossible. How do you know?”</p>
<p>“Because, Herv,” said Loog, with the impatient air of someone explaining something to a toddler, “he told me, and I saw. He escaped Ari using the fire, and scared away her capybara. The first time, he even floated down while he was unconscious.”</p>
<p>“Let’s see, then,” Herv grabbed Merscythe's arm and muttered a chant. Merscythe didn’t know the language, but somehow understood it. Herv was blown backward, sparks flying.</p>
<p>Herv shook with excitement, “A real wizard!” he exclaimed. “This kid has enough power in him to fold time!”</p>
<p>“Really?!” exclaimed Merscythe.</p>
<p>“Yes,” said Herv, “with months and months of practice. I can teach you to control magic.” </p>
<p>“Good. I need to be careful with a crazy little elf chasing after me.”</p>
<p>“Listen, kid. Ari isn’t here. She’s trapped in prison.”</p>
<p>“No she’s not! I saw her! She was there!”</p>
<p>Herv smiled, as though Merscythe amused him.</p>
<p>“You want proof? Well, I’m sorry. I can’t make Ari appear out</break> of nowhere.”</p>
<p>“Well, not yet,” Herv winked. “Just kidding. No one’s that powerful. You can’t teleport others. And Ari’s good, but not good enough to escape from prison. It’s impossible. The UFOS captured Ari and threw her onto a rock. Prisoners either die from boredom or lose the will to live. That normally happens two years after they’re put there, once they figure out that there’s no way to escape. It’s been two years since Ari was thrown into jail. She’s a goner.”</p>
<p>“Yes, yes, very dramatic,” said Loog, cutting him off. “Merscythe, Ari is dangerous, no doubt. And I believe that she’s at large now. But she’s not our priority. We need your help, plain and simple. You’re the last wizard. With your green fire and that Codue in your pocket, you have the power to vanquish Verin and restore peace to this world.”</p>
<p>Merscythe pulled the Codue out. “How do you know about the Codue? And why do I use it?”</p>
<p>Loog grinned slyly. “I know a lot of things. Herv can teach you about magic, but no one can teach you more about Python than me. That Codue you’ve got is really rare. It was designed over hundreds of years, using old magic taught by Merlin himself and the gnomes and elves’ scientific advances. By now, you’ve probably realized that you </break> can program objects everywhere. This tool was meant for you, Merscythe. It’s your sword. You have the power to unite magic and science and liberate us from the oppressor.”</p>
<p>“Why me?” Merscythe asked. He wasn’t whining or even necessarily upset, but he had been taken from his normal life in Pennsylvania and thrust into this mysterious world.</p>
<p>Loog grinned again. “If not you, who?”</p>
<p>Merscythe was trying to think of a witty retort. Then suddenly, there was a massive explosion at their feet. The entire room filled with smoke and flame as he was blown into the air and landed hard against a wall. He winced and tried to get up, but couldn’t. “Loog!” he yelled, winded. His voice sounded faint, and there was a tinny ringing in his ears. He looked around the room, but the smoke was still too thick to see anyone. Then, suddenly, Herv appeared from the smoke, coughing and wheezing. He collapsed in front of Merscythe, and gasped, “They’ve got him.”</p>
<p>Merscythe was confused and scared. Who had whom? The smoke was starting to clear, and dust was settling in the room. He saw that a perfectly circular hole had been blown through the elevator doors, but the Argenglass floor and walls were still intact. The floor had a large burn mark a few feet from where they had been standing, but no other signs of damage. Loog was nowhere to be seen.</p>]]>
</Data>
</Chapter>