<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
	<Title>Chapter 2: The Magnificent One</Title>
	<Data><![CDATA[<p>As soon as Merscythe unlocked the tree door by changing and running the program, the door disappeared. To his surprise, the entire tree floated upward. Underneath, there was a hole. Merscythe peered down and saw a gently sloping slide. He said to himself, “Well, wherever this leads, it can’t be any worse than this party.” Slipping the Codue back into his pocket, he stepped in.</p><p>Merscythe instantly regretted his decision. The slide seemed endless, and grew steeper and steeper. Soon, he was rocketing downward at what felt like 150 miles per hour. Just as he was wondering how deep below ground he was, the slide disappeared from beneath him and he shot out, landing on his back on a gigantic, spongey cushion. He heard footsteps strut up to the cushion, but didn’t see anyone.</p><p>“Aha!” said a voice. It sounded female. “So this is the package.”</p><p>Merscythe looked around frantically. The cushion was at the center of a circular, brightly lit room with no windows: some kind of futuristic lab. <i>Package?</i> he wondered. <i>And who is she talking to?</i></p><p>“It’s quite small,” remarked the person. “This isn’t even the one we ordered, but I suppose it will do.”</p><p>By now, Merscythe was annoyed. He was a person, not some </break> discounted item purchased online. The other person thought differently. “On the bright side, this one will save us a few dollars and a week of planning. It will look lovely on my wall. After it has served its purpose, that is.”</p><p>Merscythe sat up. This time, he looked down and saw the person, or creature, that was looking at him. It was about three feet tall: female, but not human. It had smaller pupils and pointier ears. It...<i>she</i> wore a purple dress, with long, black hair and bright hazel eyes full of malice. Even though Merscythe was two feet taller than the person, he felt a bit afraid of her.</p><p>“Hello, erm…human. I am your leader, Ari. You may call me Queen Ari, Master Ari, Madam Ari, or The Magnificent One.”</p><p>“What are you?” asked Merscythe.</p><p>“Me? I am your leader, Queen Ari. Ari the Magnificent. Ari—”</p><p>“No, like, what species are you?”</p><p>“Queen.”</p><p>“Never mind.”</p><p>“Now, enough chatter. I need your blood.” Ari snapped her fingers and two burly men-like creatures lifted Merscythe up. They were as short as she was, but with disproportionately large, ugly heads. One was slightly taller than the other. They carried him to a table. The taller one had a lethal looking </break>syringe in his hand.</p><p>Merscythe was hysterical. The two men strapped him to the table.</p><p>“With a human’s blood, I can destroy them. With the weapon of the foe, you can overthrow!”</p><p><i>Couplets?</i> thought Merscythe, even though he was going to die. <i>This seems a bit weird.</i></p><p>The taller dwarf-man inserted the syringe  into  Merscythe’s right arm.</p><p><i>Ow</i>, thought Merscythe. All the feeling left his arm.</p><p>Merscythe suddenly became unusually calm. He heard a voice in his mind whispering words in a language he had never heard before. His eyes felt warm. He felt a sharp pain in his head. Suddenly, flames erupted on his arms. These were not your typical orange flames. They were bright green, and felt colder than ice to the touch.</p><p>The short men screamed and ran. Apparently they didn't like green fire. Even Ari backed away.</p><p>“<i>Asa kalaad!</i>” she screeched. “Fire of the Wraiths!”</p><p>The pain in Merscythe's head was too much to bear. He yelled something and unleashed a massive explosion. Green light lit up the room and Merscythe was thrown sky-high.</p><p>As he started to drop towards the ground, he realized that he </break> wasn’t plummeting, but floating gently downward. Merscythe softly landed on his back on the polished tile floor. Then the pain in his head overcame him and he blacked out.</p><p>When Merscythe came to, he was still lying on the cold floor. The pain in his head had faded away. He gingerly pushed himself up and looked around. The lab was deserted. Ari and the two men must have left. This gave him a chance to look around the strange room he was in. What was this place?</p><p>Directly in front of him, piled twenty feet high, were metal shelves of small glass vials, all filled with bright blue, red, and green liquids. Next to the lowest shelf was a row of five faucets set into the wall. On his right were three massive, empty cages with thick steel bars. Behind him was a small table with some complex-looking instruments, and a larger one that he recognized as the one he had been strapped to. There were four doors without handles leading out from the room. On his left was the biggest one, which had a small screen and keypad next to it.</p><p>He walked to this door and pushed it hard. It was either locked or too heavy to open. He turned his attention to the screen, where a short computer program was written. Merscythe clicked the Run button on the editor. A blinking cursor appeared on the screen. IDENTIFY YOURSELF. Curious, Merscythe entered his name. M E R S C Y T H E</p></break><p>The program output with these three lines was displayed on the screen:</p><p><b>Hello, Merscythe</b></p><p><b>Access denied</b></p><p><b>Alarm triggered</b></p><br></br><p>Merscythe got the sinking feeling that he might have done something wrong. Suddenly, a siren started wailing. The room was momentarily plunged into darkness before red lights started flashing around the perimeter.</p>]]></Data>
</Chapter>