<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Chapter>
     <Title>Python Question 6</Title>
     <Data>To enter Ari's ship surreptitiously, Merscythe has to write a program that can break the code of the locked entrance to the Ariester, Ari's ship.  The Ship class has the following method, which takes a number in the range 0 to 99,999 as argument, to unlock an entrance:
unlock_entrance(code)
After an entrance has been locked with a specific five digit secret code, it can only be unlocked using the same code. For example, the following code statements attempt to unlock the entrance with the code 11111.
ariester = Ship()
ariester.unlock_entrance(11111)
The entrance would unlock only if the code supplied is the same as the secret code that was used to lock it.  The method is_entrance_locked can be used to test whether the door is locked. This method does not take any arguments and returns a value of True if the entrance is locked; otherwise, it returns False.
Merscythe can unlock the entrance by trying all codes in the range 0 to 99,999 as arguments to the unlock_entrance method. However, this would be tedious and time consuming, and it would be more efficient to use a while loop. Using a while loop, write a program that can unlock this entrance. After the program is run successfully, Chapter 7 will be unlocked.</Data>
	<Instruction>
		<ExpectedOutput><![CDATA[ <samp>Ariester main entrance unlocked</samp> ]]></ExpectedOutput>
		<Code><![CDATA[
			<table>
			    <tr>
					<th>class Ship</th>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<th>Method</th>
					<th>Description</th>
				</tr>
					<td>unlock_entrance(code)</td>
					<td>Method to unlock entrance of Ship if code is supplied as argument is correct.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>lock_entrance(code)</td>
					<td>Method to lock entrance of Ship if code is supplied as argument is correct.</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td>is_entrance_locked()</td>
					<td>Method returns True if entrance is locked; otherwise, it returns False</td>
				</tr>
			</table>
			]]>
		</Code>
	</Instruction>
</Chapter>
